Now, the switch statement here is testing whether the spice level
好了 此处 switch 语句的作用是 测试整数变量
integer variable is equal to a list of possible values.
spiceLevel 是否等于 一系列可能的值
If the spice level is 0, let's go ahead and step through the code,
如果 spiceLevel 为 0 我们来 浏览代码
which means it doesn't equal 1, it doesn't equal 2 or 3 or 4.
也就是说它不等于 1 也不等于 2、3 或 4
So we can skip these cases and
所以可以跳过这些 case
that means it's going to fall into the default case.
也就是说 将进入 default 条件
So we set the flavor to be not spicy.
因此将 flavor 的值设为 not spicy
Now what happens when the spice level is 2?
那么接下来 如果 spiceLevel 为 2 呢？
That means it doesn't evaluate in the first case for 1, so
也就是说 它并不会在第一个 等于 1 的 case 中赋值
we skip that case but it does equal 2.
因此跳过第一个 case 但因为值等于 2
So it falls into the second case which sets the flavor string to be medium,
所以进入第二个 case 令字符串 flavor 设为 medium
all right.
好了
Now this case is interesting.
现在下面这种情况有些难度
What happens when the spice level is 3?
如果 spiceLevel 为 3 呢？
Now, looking into our code, we fall into case 3 and we set the flavor to be hot.
观察一下代码 此时符合第三个 case 令 flavor 设为 hot
But there's no break statement.
但这里没有 break 语句
So we're actually going to fall into the 4th case,
因此 实际上我们来到了 第四个 case 里
which sets the flavor string to very hot.
字符串 flavor 被设为了 very hot
Now that just means we just overrode the flavor variable with a new value.
这是因为新值刚刚 覆盖了 flavor 变量
Then we hit a break statement, which will execute our switch statement.
然后碰到 break 语句 运行 switch 语句
So the latest value of the flavor string when we exit the switch statement
因此当跳出 switch 语句时 字符串 flavor 最新的值
is actually very hot.
实际上等于 very hot
The last few cases are fairly straightforward.
最后几种情况比较 直接易懂
For a spiceLevel of 1, the flavor is going to be mild.
当 spiceLevel 等于 1 时 flavor 为 mild
For a spiceLevel of 4, the flavor is also going to be very hot.
当 spiceLevel 等于 4 时 flavor 也是 very hot
And then lastly, for a spiceLevel of 10, there is no explicit case.
最后 当 spiceLevel 等于 10 时 不符合任何 case
So we fall into the default case again, and that flavor is not spicy.
因此再次进入 default flavor 为 not spicy
Great work.
干得好
Hope you got some good practice in,
希望大家好好练习
and feel more comfortable with switch statements.
能够熟练掌握 switch 语句